Dorothy Smith Dushkin Papers, 1906-1989
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
Dorothy Dushkin papers
1906-1989
Dushkin, Dorothy
MS 243
15 boxes (9 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
Composer and co-founder of music schools. Musical scores and recordings make up a large portion of the collection. Dushkin's diaries, kept from age 15 to 84, are highly detailed and personal and reflect a dual life as professional composer and family caretaker. Winnetka and Kinhaven music schools are documented by correspondence, writings, and photographs. Correspondents include Jessie Lloyd O'Connor, Caroline Bedell Thomas, and musician Nadia Boulanger.
Dorothy Brewster Smith was born in Chicago in 1903. She attended public schools in Glencoe and Winnetka, Illinois, and Bradford Academy in Massachusetts. She was graduated from Smith College with honors in music in 1925. A year later she went to Paris to study composition with Nadia Boulanger, where she met her future husband, David Dushkin, another Boulanger student.
David Dushkin was born in 1898 in a part of Russia that is now part of Poland. He emigrated to New York City with his family as a young child and grew up helping his father to run a kosher butcher shop. He spent one year at City College of New York and served in the army medical corps.
After returning to the United States from Paris, Dorothy Smith and David Dushkin both taught music in the Chicago area. They married in 1930.
In 1931 the Dushkins founded the School of Musical Arts and Crafts in Winnetka with the intention of using experimental teaching methods to stimulate creativity. Students made instruments in a shop, played in ensembles, and did ear training through games and puzzles. The Dushkins built a school/residence in 1934. During their tenure, the school was renamed the Dushkin School of Music, and finally, the Winnetka School of Music. After their departure, the school was taken over by the parents and operated as the Music Center of the North Shore.
In 1952, the Dushkin family, which by then included four children (Lelah, Nadia, David Alex, and Amanda), moved to Weston, Vermont. There Dorothy and David began the Kinhaven School of Music, a summer school devoted to chamber, orchestral, and choral music for musically gifted young people. At Kinhaven, the Dushkins continued to experiment with and adapt the basics of music education, shaping an intensive seven-week musical experience. In 1962 the school became a non-profit corporation with an elected board of trustees.
Dorothy Dushkin composed intermittently throughout her adult life. Her musical drama, "Poltarnees," was performed at her Smith College commencement. While teaching and helping to run the music schools in Illinois and Vermont, she composed many works for a wide variety of ensembles, instrumental and vocal, often tailoring her compositions to the needs of young novices. These works have been performed regularly at Kinhaven and all over the United States.
David Dushkin died in 1986. Dorothy Dushkin moved to Manchester, Vermont, in 1987 and later to Amherst, Massachusetts. Dorothy Dushkin died on March 3, 1992.
The Dorothy Dushkin Papers occupy nine linear feet of shelf space and consist of correspondence; diaries and other writings; scrapbooks; photographs; memorabilia; scores; tape and disc recordings; and miscellaneous papers. The material documents Dorothy's life from the time she began her diary at age 15. David Dushkin's papers are primarily related to his post-marriage life.
While the bulk of these papers belong to Dorothy Smith Dushkin, a substantial portion were generated by David Dushkin, and especially in Series V, "Professional Activities," their papers are somewhat intertwined, as were their professional lives. Series I through IV contain largely personal papers, but to the extent that the Dushkins' professional and personal lives overlapped, this distinction is somewhat artificial. For instance, Dorothy's diaries are a highly personal account of her emotional life in which she writes of her dual identities as composer and family caretaker. The diaries, kept faithfully from age 15 to 84, are exceptionally introspective and reflect a lifelong tension between these identities. They reveal a passionate woman coping with, among other things, the worry and strain of many commitments, the untimely death of a daughter from cancer, and the health challenges of aging. The carefree girl of 1919 becomes a sometimes frustrated woman trying simultaneously to satisfy her creative urges and maintain her many responsibilities.
The personal correspondence is indicative of the ways in which music was a large part of each of the Dushkins' lives. The bulk of the family correspondence consists of letters received by Dorothy and David, though a significant number were written by them. Of special interest is the correspondence between David and his brother, Alex, and sister, Eva Kassan, living in Israel during the 1960s and 1970s. These letters and a number of others were apparently selected by Dorothy from "masses of family correspondence [from which she] saved just a random pile to represent extended family." Correspondence with friends and associates includes many of Dorothy's Smith College friends and professors, notably Jessie Lloyd O'Connor '25, Caroline Bedell Thomas '25, Ross Lee Finney, and Werner Josten. The most famous Dushkin correspondent was Nadia Boulanger, who wrote 14 letters and notes between 1926 and 1976. The family memorabilia and photograph collection is extensive, providing especially thorough documentation of the Dushkin children's activities. The discs, which recorded family events from baby noises to musical performances, are the equivalent of home movies. The scrapbooks also contain material related to the Dushkins' early teaching careers and activities at the Winnetka school.
The bulk of professional papers relate to Dorothy's composing. She kept much of her correspondence with publishers and a special file of programs, clippings and correspondence related to performances of her work. This material reflects her unstinting efforts to get her work the attention it deserved, sometimes successfully, but often with discouraging results. The scores of orchestral, chamber, solo, and other works constitute Dorothy Dushkin's major output as a composer. Most of the tape recordings are of performances of her work, many of which took place at Kinhaven Music School. Both Dushkins were interested in recorder manufacture and repertory, but the correspondence reflects David's more active involvement in this aspect of their professional lives. Dorothy and David participated equally in the founding and running of the two music schools, though it appears from the papers that David's role was more prominent while Dorothy did more work behind-the-scenes.
The general correspondence concerns miscellaneous professional activities of both Dushkins, such as their early teaching careers and the wide-ranging musical interests they shared with former colleagues, students, and parents of students. Throughout the correspondence there is evidence of the influence of the Dushkins' innovative educational theories on many of the people who came in contact with them professionally. There is also a substantial amount of Dorothy's correspondence negotiating potential performances of her work.
This collection is organized into five series:
I. Biography
II. Personal Correspondence
III. Diaries and Other Writings
IV. Memorabilia and Photographs
V. Professional Activities
Series I is arranged alphabetically. The personal correspondence (Series II) is alphabetical within the subseries "family" and "friends and associates." (Professional correspondence is located in Series V., Professional Activities.) Within series III, the diaries are arranged chronologically. There are separate folders for Dorothy's other writings and David's poems and miscellaneous writings. Series IV is divided into the following subseries: miscellaneous memorabilia; scrapbooks; photographs; and discs. The photographs are arranged according to individual family members, family or other groups, other individuals, and places. The documentary and audiovisual materials in series V are divided into the following subseries: composing; recorder repertory and manufacture; Winnetka School of Music; Kinhaven Music School; miscellaneous; recordings; and scores.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The papers are open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection.
Additions to the Collection
Periodic additions to collection are expected.
History of the Collection
Dorothy Dushkin donated her papers to the Sophia Smith Collection in 1988. Her daughter, Lelah Dushkin, donated additional papers in 1991.
Search Terms
Composers--United States; Music--Instruction and study--United States--History--20th century--Sources; Women musicians--United States--Sources; Women composers--United States--Sources; Smith College--Students--History--Sources; Music--Manuscripts--United States; Family--United States--History--20th century--Sources; O'Connor, Jessie Lloyd, 1904- --Correspondence; Thomas, Caroline Bedell--Correspondence; Dushkin, Dorothy; Boulanger, Nadia--Correspondence; Dushkin, Samuel, 1891- --Correspondence; Dushkin, Alexander M. (Alexander Mordecai), 1890-1976-Correspondence
Additional Information
Related Material
Related correspondence is located in the Jessie Lloyd O'Connor and Caroline Bedell Thomas Papers. Other unpublished material can be found in the College Archives files for the class of 1925, and the papers of Dorothy Dushkin's sister, Gertrude Smith, a member of the music department faculty for many years.
- Series I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL
  - Amanda Dushkin: teacher's evaluation, eulogy, and memorial scholarship 1947-75 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - David Dushkin: obituaries, memorial booklet, and other biographical information 1986, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Dorothy Smith Dushkin: letter of recommendation 1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lelah, Nadia, and David Alex Dushkin: clippings 1969, 1980, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Samuel Dushkin: obituary 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4a)
  - Gertrude Parker Smith: obituary 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4b)
  - Gertrude Judd Smith 1899, undated (Box 1, Folder 4c)
- Series II. PERSONAL CORRESPONDENCE
  - Family
    - Alex and Julia Dushkin to Dorothy and David Dushkin 1958-73, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Amanda Dushkin to parents 1959-60, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - David Dushkin to family
      - Alex and Julia Dushkin 1962-73 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - David Alex and Valerie Dushkin (includes letter to grandson, Peter Dushkin) 1950-71, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Dorothy Smith 1927-29 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Dorothy Smith Dushkin 1935-49 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Dorothy Smith Dushkin undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Lelah Dushkin 1950-70 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Nadia (Dushkin) and Carey McIntosh 1964-70 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Sam and Louise Dushkin 1964-74 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Eva (Dushkin) and Shalom Kassan 1958-72 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Gertrude Smith 1963-69 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Miscellaneous family 1968-72 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - David Alex "Vadi" Dushkin to family
      - First year at Cambridge School) 1950-51 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - 1958-61, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Nana 1948, 1954, undated (Box 1, Folder 19a)
    - David Alex and Valerie Dushkin to David and Dorothy Dushkin 1968-71, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Dorothy Smith Dushkin to family
      - Parents 1919-54, undated (Box 1, Folder 21-21a)
      - David Dushkin 1927-29 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - David Dushkin 1938-71, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Nadia Dushkin 1965 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Gertrude Smith 1921-65, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Lelah Dushkin to family
      - While at Smith College 1947-51 (Box 1a, Folder 1)
      - 1964-69, undated (Box 1a, Folder 2)
      - Nanna 1948-59, undated (Box 1a, Folder 3)
    - Sam and Louise Dushkin to David and Dorothy Dushkin 1930-64 (Box 1a, Folder 4)
    - Eva (Dushkin) and Shalom Kassan to David and Dorothy Dushkin 1958-74 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Nadia Dushkin [McIntosh] to family 1940-46 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Nadia Duskin to Nanna 1950, undated (Box 2, Folder 2a)
    - Nadia (Dushkin) and Carey McIntosh to Dorothy and David Dushkin 1961-64, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Gertrude (Judd) and Henry T. Smith to Dorothy Smith Dushkin 1920-47, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Gertrude "Trudle" Smith to Dorothy and David Dushkin 1930-69, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous 1923-29, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Friends and associates
    - Dorothy and David Dushkin to friends and associates 1961-82 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Dorothy Bolle to Dorothy and David Dushkin 1961-84, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Nadia Boulanger to Dorothy (Smith) and David Dushkin 1926-76, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Josephine Crisfield Connerat to Dorothy Smith Dushkin 1926-83 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Ross Lee Finney to Dorothy Smith Dushkin, (includes letter from Carrie M. Finney) 1928-1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Foster Parents Plan for War Children, Inc. to Dorothy Dushkin (includes letters from foster children) 1951-57 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Malin Guettler to Dorothy Smith 1926-27, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Betty and Barbara "Bobby" Ickes to Dorothy Dushkin 1978-79 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Werner Josten to Dorothy Smith 1925-29, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Amanda Bryan Kane to Dorothy Smith Dushkin 1930-85 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Mary Norris Lloyd to Dorothy Dushkin 1977-84, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Jessie Lloyd O'Connor to Dorothy Smith Dushkin 1929-84 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Smith College 1962-83 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Susan Stockhammer to Dorothy and David Dushkin 1971-74 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Thomas Whitney Surette to Dorothy Smith 1925-27 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Geraldine Clark Mandell Sylvester to Dorothy Smith Dushkin 1928-85, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Alice and Fay Taylor to Dorothy and David Dushkin 1957-85 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Caroline Bedell Thomas to Dorothy Smith Dushkin 1925-85, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous friends and associates of Dorothy (Smith) and David Dushkin 1926-85 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Letters and cards to Dorothy Dushkin following David Dushkin's death 1986 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Unidentified 1926-58, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Series III. DIARIES AND OTHER WRITINGS
  - Diaries of Dorothy Smith Dushkin, 1919-87
    - 19 Jun 1919-14 Jul 1926 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 12 Aug 1926-23 Jan 1936 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 26 Jan 1936-20 May 1945 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Jan 1947-5 Dec 1966 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 1 Jan 1967-11 Dec 1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - 14 Jan 1974-31 Dec 1981 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 4 Jan 1982-4 Sep 1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 4 Sep 1987-10 Jul 1988 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Writings
    - "Data on Diabetes," 1982-89 and record of garden 1957-86 (Box 3a, Folder 1)
    - Poems, lecture, and articles 1973, undated (Box 3a, Folder 2)
    - "The Glassy Interval" (manuscript of diary excerpts) undated (Box 3a, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence re: publication of "The Glassy Interval" 1986-87, undated (Box 3a, Folder 4)
    - David Dushkin: Poems and miscellaneous 1956-57, undated (Box 3a, Folder 5)
- Series IV. MEMORABILIA AND PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Miscellaneous memorabilia
    - Clippings 1927-83 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - David and Dorothy Smith Dushkin: Programs, passports, flyers, and other miscellaneous memorabilia (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Dushkin children: Baby records, school reports, programs, flyer 1932-79, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Photographs and memorabilia 1928-37 (Box 4)
    - Photographs and memorabilia 1938-43 (Box 5)
    - Photographs 1941-60 (Box 5)
  - Photographs
    - Dorothy Smith Dushkin 1917-67, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - David Dushkin 1920s, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Dorothy and David Dushkin 1949-50, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Amanda Dushkin 1948-49, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - David Alex Dushkin ca. 1937, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Lelah Dushkin 1933-67, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Nadia Dushkin ca. 1938, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Dushkin family groups ca. 1932-1960s, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Gertrude "Trudle" Smith 1928, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Smith family ca. 1906-1960s, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Dushkin family with friends 1920s-1970s (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous family, friends, and associates (includes portrait of Igor Stravinsky) 1926, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Homes, schools, and miscellaneous scenes 1908-42, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Discs
    - Dorothy Smith Dushkin singing "Les Roses d'Ispahan" 1931; Mrs. Jent singing Mrs. Reed's song (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Clair de Lune," 1931; Gertrude Smith playing "Kreisleriana (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Dushkin children 1932-40 (Box 7, Folder 3-15)
    - Swami, Vishwananda, visit to Dushkin home ca. 1940 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Lelah Dushkin undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - David Alex Dushkin [?] undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - "Test recording of clarison improvisation" and Lelah Dushkin (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Dorothy Dushkin, "Trial recording of Handel Recorder Sonata in F" (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Saint-Saens [?]: Dorothy Smith Dushkin, voice; Gertrude Smith, piano (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - "Dushkin family ensembles" (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Dorothy Smith Dushkin, "voice--Faure," accompanied by Gertrude Smith (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Dorothy Smith Dushkin, "German songs" (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Kinhaven performances 1977 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Series V. PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES
  - Composing
    - Performances of Dorothy Dushkin compositions: Programs, clippings, and correspondence
      - 1950-84 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - 1985-88 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Newsletters, clippings, and brochures 1986-87, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Copyright applications 1942-63 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with publishers
      - Carl Fischer, Inc. 1952-84 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Galaxy Music Corporation 1960-82 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Musica Rara 1971-87 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Shawnee Press, Inc. 1976-84 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - The Valley Music Press (Smith College) 1956-86 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous 1962-86 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Recorder music and manufacture
    - General correspondence 1934-83 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Requests for music 1959-67 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Dushkin Recorder Co. publicity undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Proposal for book about recorders by David Dushkin: grant application and correspondence 1956 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Winnetka School of Music
    - General correspondence 1931-54 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Property sale correspondence and legal documents 1952-55 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Writings by Dushkins and others 1928-44, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Programs, brochures, and clippings 1952-71 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Photographs 1933-1940s (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Kinhaven Music School
    - General correspondence 1956-82 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Contributers 1964 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - "Camp memos (diary)" by David Dushkin 28 Nov 1965-12 Sep 1967 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Writings and memorabilia (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Scrapbook: "In Celebration of the First Thirty Years of Kinhaven Music School the Alumni Collect and Present this Album to David and Dorothy Dushkin August 23, 1981" (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Book of greetings to the Dushkin's on Dorothy's birthday 26 July 1985 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Awards 1978-85 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - David Dushkin: Contracts with publishers 1925-34 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - General correspondence
      - 1929-69 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - 1970-79 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - 1980-87 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - Leopold and Evangeline Stokowski 1931-35 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - Millicent Taylor (Christian Science Monitor) 1936-55, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Recordings
    - Cassettes of Dorothy Smith Dushkin compositions (some tapes include other composers)
      - "Concerto for Piano and Orchestra" and "Sonata for Horn and Piano" (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - "Eight Voices": student orchestra, University of Western Ontario, Jeff Stokes, conductor (includes pieces by other composers) (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - "Fantasy for Three": The Pone Ensemble 9 Feb 1988 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - "Quartet in D Minor" for four recorders: student recital, Kalamazoo, Michigan 13 Jun 1982 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - "Septet for Brass," and "Sonata for Horn and Piano," 25 May 1982 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - "Sonata for Flute and Piano" (1972): Robin Hendrich, flute, Philip Kraft, piano, Boston 1 May 1986 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - "Sonata for Flute and Piano," "Pour S'Amuser" for marimba quartet, "Quintet for Horns," and "Sonata for Two Cellos and Piano" (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - "Ten Poems in a Filagree for Women's Choir" (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - "Ten Poems in a Filigree for Women's Choir," sung by Lehigh University Choir, J. Bidlack, conductor (Box 10, Folder 8a)
      - "The Light of Man" (Box 10, Folder 8b)
    - Other and unknown composers
      - David Dushkin Memorial Concert, Kinhaven 18 Jul 1987 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Focus on Women in the Arts, alumnae concert, Smith College 5 May 1982 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Vytas J. Baksys, Master of Music piano recital, SUNY-Stony Brook 22 Nov 1983 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Vytas J. Baksys and Terry Kowal, piano duo recital 25 April 1985 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Lawrence Willingham performances (Box 10, Folder 13-14)
    - Reel-to-reel recordings of Dorothy Smith Dushkin compositions (some tapes include other composers)
      - "Canaan Bound" (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - "Canaan Bound" ("Not as good as original," D.D.) (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - "Canaan Bound" (master tape for 1976 record) (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Pieces by Dvorak and Stravinsky (Box 11)
      - "Claviquint III": Lisa Hardaway, flute; Peter Reit, horn; Gilda Joffe, violin; Karl Parens, cello; Vytas Baksys, piano; Kinhaven Jul 1974 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - "Concerto for Piano and Orchestra": Leslie Spotz, piano; Kinhaven Chamber Orchestra, Jerry Bidlack, conductor; 2 Aug 1980 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - "Pour S'Amuser," suite for marimba and woodwinds in five movements 9 Aug 1980 (Box 11)
      - "Episode No. 2": Daniel Maki, flute; Joe Contino, clarinet; Bob Moore, bassoon (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - "Episode No. 3": Daniel Maki, flute; Joe Contino, clarinet; Bob Moore, bassoon (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - "Interlude for Horn and Strings," Kinhaven 1971 (Box 11, Folder 7a)
      - "Retrospective," Kinhaven 1971 (Box 11)
      - "Interpretations" (copy from Kinhaven master) 22 Oct 1981 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - "Interpretations" cantata, Kinhaven 16 Aug 1981 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - "Kinhaven Concerto" for orchestra: The Kinhaven Orchestra, Jerry T. Bidlack, conductor, Kinhaven ("Not good recording, uneven balances") 1974 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - "Percussion Plus": The Kinhaven Percussion Ensemble, Randall Edson, Director; Diane Rudolph, flute; Ben Parker, string bass (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - "Percussion Suite No. 2," Kinhaven 3 Jul 1972 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - "Time Out," Kinhaven 3 Jul 1972 (Box 11)
      - "Precision Patterns": [Kinhaven Percussion Ensemble?], Randall Edson, director; Kinhaven Summer 1971 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - "Quartet Opus 44" (two movements), and pieces by other composers, Kinhaven staff concert 8 Aug 1981 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - "Quartet Opus 44 for piano, flute, clarinet, and bassoon, performed by K. Moore, D. Melle, E. Marks, R. Moore, BGSU College of Musical Arts, Bryan Hall 25 Apr 1981 (Box 11, Folder 15)